Sylvia Beach Papers, 1887-1966 (bulk 1920s-1950s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1901-1970; 39 boxes (1 partial)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1923-1955; 4 folders
    - Hemingway, Ernest, circa 1925 December 14; portion of 1 folder Autograph letter. (Folder 8)
      Top half of the letter is written by Ernest Hemingway and bottom half is written by Hadley.
    - Beach, Sylvia to Ernest Hemingway, 1925-1955; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1928; portion of 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1928 September 15; portion of 1 folder Autograph postcard. (Folder 10)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1928 September 24; portion of 1 folder Autograph letter. (Folder 10)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1928 November 14; portion of 1 folder Autograph letter. (Folder 10)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1928 December 14; portion of 1 folder Autograph Christmas card. (Folder 10)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1929; portion of 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1929 February 12; portion of 1 folder Autograph letter. (Folder 11)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1929 August 18; portion of 1 folder Autograph letter. (Folder 11)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1930; portion of 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Hemingway, Ernest: Autograph Note on Book Jacket of The Sun Also Rises, 1930; portion of 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, 1931; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      Envelope only.
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, undated; portion of 1 folder Autograph letter. (Folder 14)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Hemingway, Ernest to Sylvia Beach, undated; portion of 1 folder Autograph letter. (Folder 14)
  - Hemingway, "Puck" & Jack to Sylvia Beach, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    Jack is John H. N. Hemingway, oldest son of Ernest Hemingway, born in Toronto on October 10, 1923, and raised as a child in Paris. "Puck" is Jack's wife.
  - Henry, Georgette, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - d'Herbais de Thun, Mimie, 1944 September 13; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Herbart, Elizabeth, 1944 June 29-1962 May 23; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Herrick, Kitty (Mrs. P. W.), undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Herring, Robert, 1937 July-1948 June 3; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Hervey, Sybil, undated; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Hesse, Helen A., 1929 April 13; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Heurtault, L., 1918 June 15; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Hickman, Rolland H., 1946 December 18; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Higgins, Lawrence, undated; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Hills, Gordon, undated; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Hillyer, Helen H., 1950 October 25-1951 May 12; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Hinman, Jane, 1933-1962; 2 folders (Folder 28-29)
  - Hitchcock, W. A., undated; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Hodge, Sarah M., 1937 April 5; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - Hoetis, Themistocles, 1948 December 4; 1 folder (Folder 32)
  - Hoffmeister, Adolf, undated; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Hollard, Mireille, 1939 April 7; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Honda, Zenichiro, 1922 April 25; 1 folder (Folder 35)
  - Hood, Sheila, 1958 April 22-May 12; 1 folder (Folder 36)
  - Hopkins, Gerard, 1934 November 8-December 8; 1 folder (Folder 37)
  - Hoppenot, Henri, 1944 October 10-1960 December 14; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Horner, David, 1940 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Hoskins, Dorothy, 1938 May 27; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Houghton, Laura, 1960 November 5-1969 November 20; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Huddleston, Sisley, 1928 June 20-1929 December 17; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Hudson, Elizabeth, 1935 September 10-1936 May 29; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Huebsch, B. W., 1922 November 8-1950 September 25; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Hughes, Toni, 1959 March 23-May 26; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Humbrecht, George, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Hume, Mrs. James Cleland, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Hutchins, Patricia, 1947 February 12-1951 November 11; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Hutchison, Hazel C., 1929 December 18; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Hyde, Freda, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Illone, Betsy, 1958 January 3; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - International Business Organisation, 1958 August 12; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Irons, Jessica I., 1958; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Isherwood, Christopher, 1935 July 6-1937 April 8; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Jaggard, Charles H., 1933 March 21; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    AM 20997
  - Jeans, Norah M., 1938 November 14; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Johnston, W. Dawson, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Jolas, Betsy, undated; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Jolas, Eugene, 1924 November 21-1938 December 20; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Jolas, Maria, 1935 March 13-1970 March 22; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Jones, Henry Festing, 1921 August 20-1928 December; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Jones, William R., 1935 October 11; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Jouby, Louis, 1962 September 24; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Joyce, George, 1923-1932; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Joyce, Helen, 1960 October 17-1961 March 10; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Joyce, James, 1926-1961; 3 folders
    - Joyce, James to Sylvia Beach, 1926-1961; 1 folder (Folder 29)
      From the James Joyce Collection, Lockwood Memorial Library, University of Buffalo.
    - Joyce, James to Sylvia Beach and Herbert Gorman, 1928-1939; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Joyce, James, Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - Joyce, Lucia, 1958-1962; 2 folders
    - Joyce, Lucia to Sylvia Beach, 1958-1960; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Joyce, Lucia to Sylvia Beach, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Joyce, Stanislaus, 1926 February 13; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Kahane, Jack, 1932 September 10-1939 November; 1 folder (Folder 35)
  - Kain, Richard M., 1948 July 4-1960 March 13; 1 folder (Folder 36)
  - Katta, T., 1927 August 17; 1 folder (Folder 37)
  - Katz, Leslie, 1958 January 27-1962 September 2; 1 folder (Folder 38)
  - Keller, Adolf, 1926 May 29; 1 folder (Folder 39)
  - Keller, Thomas G., 1930 January 13; 1 folder (Folder 40)
  - Kelly, Matilde, 1924 December 9-December 13; 1 folder (Folder 41)
  - de Kerdrel Raoul A., 1944 September 19; 1 folder (Folder 42)
  - de Kergarion, Renee, undated; 1 folder (Folder 43)
  - Keynes, Geoffrey, 1933 April 2-16; 1 folder (Folder 44)
  - Kilgour, Bayard L., Jr., 1960 October 17-1961 July 25; 1 folder (Folder 45)
  - Killen, A. M., 1929 January 1-1940 April 30; 1 folder (Folder 46)
  - King, Clinton, 1961 September 4-26; 1 folder (Folder 47)
  - King, Raphael, 1935 September 9-1936 July 2; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Kingsbury, Muriel, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1927 January 19; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Klein, L., 1943 November 30; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Klein, Marc, 1946 September 3-November 14; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Knerr, Anthony, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Knodel, Arthur, 1950 June 5-1962 May 30; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Knoll, Robert E., 1961 November 11; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Koch, Kenneth, 1955 August 16; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Kohlberg, Lore, 1957 October 8; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Kraft, James, 1959 May 10; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Kramer, Louis L., undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Labesse, Paul, 1928 March 8; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1951 May 3-21; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Lafourcade, Georges, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Lagden, Mervyne, 1937 November 30; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Lalanne, Philias, 1939 December 20; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Lalou, René, 1937 October 26-1954 December 22; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Lamont, Harry, 1960 September 7-November 2; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Lamotte, Angèle, 1945; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Lamy, Marthe, undated; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - de Lanux, Pierre, undated; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Larbaud, Valery, 1921 February 15-1927 December 18; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Larkin, Joseph J., 1945 February 5; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - La Rouchefoucault, E., 1959 November 4; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Larsson, R. E., 1938 March 3; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Lasselin, George, 1929 October 12; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Laughlin, James, 1936 December 30-1962 April 30; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Laughlin's, Clara (Paris Information Bureau), 1934 April 26; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Lavin, Mary, 1962 June 25; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Lawrence, D. H., 1928 April 4-1934 February 27; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - LeBlanc, Georgette, undated; 1 folder (Folder 32)
  - LeBlevennec, Amélie, 1951 February 19; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - LeBout, G., 1942 January 5; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - LeCollecter, Dilys, 1946 October 10-1961 December 29; 1 folder (Folder 35)
  - Leconte, Maurice, 1945 April 6-1946 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 36)
  - Lees, Dorothy Neville, 1921 February 3-1962 April 29; 1 folder (Folder 37)
  - Leet, Dorothy, 1951 August 24-1962 July 11; 1 folder (Folder 38)
  - LeFèvre-Pontalis, Jean-François, 1944 January 15; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - LeGallienne, Richard, 1932 April 2; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Léger, Aléxis Saint-Léger, 1951 February 24-1960 November 5; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Leiris, Michel, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Lemaître, Madame Jacques, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Lennon, Peter, 1962 July 25-September 12; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Léon, Lucie, 1952 July 2; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Léopold, Flavia, 1929 February 14; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Le Progrès, 1962 August 10; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    Includes a 5 Francs bill sent by Sylvia Beach.
  - Lereüil, Maurice, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - LeRoux, Billie, 1940 December 24-1959 March 29; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Leroy, Jean, 1959 March 18; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - de Leschetsky, Therèse, 1948 January 30; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Leslie, Seymour, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Levin, Harry, 1941; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Lewis, Grace (Mrs. Sinclair Lewis), 1946 October 30-December 3; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Lewis, Janet, 1929 October 30; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1927 March 20-1939 June 10; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Librairie Française, 1922 July 13-1923 September 3; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - "Life and Letters Today", 1939 November 24; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Light, James, 1922 July 22; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Lilley, Joan, 1962 August 7; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Lin, Fu, 1922 September 24; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Linossier-Ardoin, Alice, 1955 June 28-1962 September 1; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Linossier, Raymonde, 1926 August; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Little, Brown & Company, 1928 June 5; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Litvinoff, Ivy, 1926 October 14-1968 October 14; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Locke, Mrs. Bradford B., 1957 January; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - London, Jack, 1938 September 24; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Long, Helen, 1949 April 8-December 12; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Lorsignol, S., 1929 December 28-1950 May 23; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - Lottman, Herbert R., 1958 June 16; 1 folder (Folder 32)
  - Lowry, Malcolm, 1934 May 25; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Lubac, Jacqueline, 1948; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Lund, H., 1957 November 21; 1 folder (Folder 35)
  - Lynch, Miriam, 1953 November 6-1955 December 8; 1 folder (Folder 36)
  - Lynes, George Platt, undated; 1 folder (Folder 37)
  - MacAlister, R. A. Stewart, undated; 1 folder (Folder 38)
  - MacCarvill, Mrs. P., undated; 1 folder (Folder 39)
  - MacCoy, Marguerite to Sylvia Beach, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 40)
  - MacDonagh, Donagh, undated; 1 folder (Folder 41)
  - MacDonald, Ambassador, 1962 March 31; 1 folder (Folder 42)
  - MacDonald, Dwight, 1933 May 26-July 5; 1 folder (Folder 43)
  - Macé, Mme. Gaston, 1949 July 13-1961 December 21; 1 folder (Folder 44)
  - MacIntyre, C. F., 1946 March 3; 1 folder (Folder 45)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1927 August 15-1946 December 11; 1 folder (Folder 46)
  - MacShane, Frank, 1954 January 15; 1 folder (Folder 47)
  - Magill, M. M., undated; 1 folder (Folder 48)
  - Manfred, Ernest, 1947 August 1; 1 folder (Folder 49)
  - Mansfield, Katherine, 1954 December 14; 1 folder (Folder 50)
  - de Marcilly, L., 1940 January 8-1956 March 19; 1 folder (Folder 51)
  - Marcousé, Betty, 1927 October 21; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - de Margerie, Jenny, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Margules, de Hirsh, 1961 May 10; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Mari, D. J., undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Marichalar, Antonio, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Marsh, Philip, 1934 August 2; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Martens, Johannes S., 1961 November 25-1962 January 19; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Martin, Troy Kennedy, 1959 December 8; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Mason, Ludo C., 1931; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Massé, Henri, 1949; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Massey, A. W., 1939 September 29-1961 December 28; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Matereau, C. Daniel, 1943 October 7; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Mathews, Jackson, 1926 October 6-1961 June 9; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Mathews, Marthiel, 1955 December 2-1962 January 27; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Mayhall, Jane, 1960 April 3; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Mazon, Jacqueline, 1954 November 2-1957 July 7; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1922-1949; portions of 2 boxes
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1922; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1923; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1924; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1925; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1928; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1930; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1931; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1936; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1938; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1944; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1949; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - McAlmon, Robert, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - McCawley & Co., 1927 January 20; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - McGreevy, Thomas, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - de Menasce, Jean, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Mercanton, François, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Mercanton, Jacques, 1937 August 1-1939 July 7; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Merritt-Hawkes, O. A., 1938 January 4; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - de Messey, Marquise, undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Messineo, Léon, 1934 November 22; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Metcalf, Addison M., 1959 March 23-May 4; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Metzenberg, Mrs. John, 1948 August 7; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Meyer-Delbos, Madeleine, 1933 February 17; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Michaels, Charles, Jr., 1955 May 18; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Michaud, Regis, 1917 May 18-1927 August 9; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Micheli-Pellegrini, Pietro, 1964 December 26; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Milhaud, Madeline, 1952 June 7-1962 June 18; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Miller, Charles, 1961 October 17; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Miller, Henry, 1935 December 9-1938 November 10; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Mistral Books and Prints, 1960 April 26; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Mondadori, Arnoldo, 1961 October 13-1962 February 6; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Monnier, Adrienne, 1918-1954; 15 folders
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1918; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1923 July 9; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1929-1930; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1937; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - Beach, Sylvia to Adrienne Monnier, 1938-1943; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1938; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1939 August 12; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1943; 1 folder (Folder 37)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1946; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1948; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1949; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1950 October 20; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1951; 1 folder (Folder 42)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1953; 1 folder (Folder 43)
    - Monnier, Adrienne to Sylvia Beach, 1954; 1 folder (Folder 44)
  - Monnier, Clovis, 1943 December 31; 1 folder (Folder 45)
  - Monnier, Mathilde, undated; 1 folder (Folder 46)
  - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette), 1948-1962; portions of 2 boxes
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette) to Sylvia Beach, 1948; 1 folder Postcards (Folder 47)
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette)to Sylvia Beach, 1951-1954; 1 folder (Folder 48)
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette) to Sylvia Beach, 1955-1956; 1 folder (Folder 49)
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette) to Sylvia Beach, 1957-1958; portion of 1 folder (Folder 50)
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette) to Sylvia Beach, 1959; 1 folder (Folder 51)
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette) to Sylvia Beach, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette) to Sylvia Beach, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Monnier-Bécat, Marie (Rinette) to Sylvia Beach, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Monro, Alida, 1927 March 28-1930 February 11; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Monro, W. D., 1931 February 24; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Monro, Harriet, 1922 September 16-1948 September 21; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Montague, John, 1962 February 23; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Moore, George, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1936 October 11-1969 December 21; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Moorhead, Ethel, 1927 February 22; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Morel, Auguste, 1926 April 21-1951 April 2; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Morgan, B. H., 1958 December-1959 March 12; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Morgan, Louise, 1944 November 18-1962 January 8; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Morley, Christopher, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Morley, Mrs. Frederick H., undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Morot-Sir, Catherine, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Morot-Sir, Jacqueline, 1961 April 13; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Morris, Mary to Eleanor (Cyprian) and Sylvia Beach, 1917-1920; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Mort, Kenneth, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Moschos, Louise, 1952; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Moschos, Wilhelmine, 1926 July 24; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Munro, Meeda, 1933 March 3; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Muoi, Doan, 1939 February 25; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Nau, Naja, 1925 December 10; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Nedeljkovitch, Stanoye, 1917 December 31; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Nevvin, Kenneth, 1936 March 31; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Newitt, Margaret, 1939 November 10-December 14; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1945 January 15; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - The New York Times, 1949 June 16-July 22; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Nicolas, H., 1962 July 24; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Norledge, Louise, 1934 December 28-1948 October; 3 folders
    - Norledge, Louise, 1934 December 28-1940 December 30; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - Norledge, Louise, 1941 June 14-1948 October; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Norledge, Louise, undated; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1946 March 18-July 24; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Norton, Barbara, 1956 October 22; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Norton-Griffiths, Sir Peter, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Les Nouvelles Littéraires, 1957 March 12; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Nutting, Helen, 1930 February 6; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - O'Brien, Frederik, 1936 September 13; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - O'Brien, Justin, 1929 October 3-1959 June 25; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - O'Brien, Minna, 1929 December 11; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - "The Observer", 1933 May; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Ocampo, Victoria, 1934 November 13-1936 March 2; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - O'Faolain, Sean, 1948 May 16; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - d'Offay, Anthony, 1961 July-1962 August 31; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Ogden, C. K., 1929 January 4-1932 September 6; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - O'Gorman, Ned, 1959 September 21-1962 February 14; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Oldenburger, Eleanor, 1947 October 30-1958 February 3; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - O'Leary, Peggy, 1929 November 18-1958 November 21; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Olympia Press, 1961 October 5-1962 January 19; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Orbison, Agnes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Orbison, Bertha, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Orbison, Douglas, 1915 January 5-1926 November 4; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Orbison, J.H., 1926 November 24; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Orbison, Kay, 1960 December 22; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Orbison, Thomas J., 1918-1933; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Orbison, Virginia, 1951; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Ould, Herman, 1929 November 27-1932 December 15; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Oxford University Press, 1934 November 5; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Paine, Albert B., undated; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Pantling, Dorothy, undated; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Parker, Constance, 1929 October 29; 1 folder (Folder 29)
  - Partlan, Anne, 1931 August 26; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Patchen, Kenneth, 1951 February 14-March 5; 1 folder (Folder 31)
  - Paul, Elliot, 1949 August 10; 1 folder (Folder 32)
  - Pauleau, Hélène, 1959 April 29-1961 December 29; 1 folder (Folder 33)
  - Pauleau, Marie-Jeanne, 1960 November 11-1961 November 5; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Paulhan, Jean, 1922 February 3-1947 July 4; 1 folder (Folder 35)
  - Peabody Book Shop, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1945 March 27-1960 January 4; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Pellesier, Michel, 1926 May 16; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Penuel Press, 1927 December 13; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Peter, Marion, 1911-1961; 6 folders
    - Beach, Sylvia to Marion Peter, 1911-1916; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Add to collection by Mrs. Peter in 1966
    - Beach, Sylvia to Marion Peter, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Beach, Sylvia to Marion Peter, 1921-1923; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      Added to collection by Mrs. Peter on 1966 March 18
    - Beach, Sylvia to Marion Peter, 1928-1961; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Beach, Sylvia to Marion Peter, 1933-1938; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Beach, Sylvia to Marion Peter, 1953-1961; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Peterson, Spiro, 1955 September 14; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Petitjean, Armand, 1934 July 19-1935 December 12; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Philipon, Remi, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Phillips, Margaret, 1960 October 15; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Picasso, Pablo, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Pichette, Henri, 1948 July 27; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Piekorski, Stefan, 1937 May 13; 1 folder (Folder 17)
  - Pierce, Ivy, 1938 April 7; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Pierre de Belay, Hélène, 1959 March 4; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - "Poetry Quarterly", 1940 March 20; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Porter, Harrison Paul, 1946 January 24-1949 July 16; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1933 November 18-1956 February 6; 1 folder (Folder 22)
  - Poujol, Jacques, undated; 1 folder (Folder 23)
  - Poulenc, Francis, undated; 1 folder (Folder 24)
  - Pound, Dorothy, 1920 September 27-1949 April 15; 1 folder (Folder 25)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1921 January 24-1959 May 16; 1 folder (Folder 26)
  - Power, Arthur, 1950 January 5; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Predoevitch, Eugenie to Sylvia Beach, 1921; 1 folder (Folder 28)
  - Prescott, Joseph, 1945-1957; 2 folders
    - Beach, Sylvia to Joseph Prescott, 1954-1956; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Prescott, Joseph to Sylvia Beach, 1945-1957; 1 folder (Folder 30)
  - Pressley, Eugene, 1938 November 18-1939 July 26; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    Includes photograph postcards of Tolstoi and of material or places related to him. Captions are in Russian with English captions on reverse side.
  - Preston, Sylvia-Letters and Cards, 1938-1961; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Prévost, Jean, 1925 April 30; 1 folder (Folder 3)